<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>IOyuk1Nya&#39;s Blog • Posts by &#34;english&#34; category</title>
        <link>https://blog.ivansnow02.xyz</link>
        <description>some notes about computer science</description>
        <language>zh-CN</language>
        <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2023 20:43:08 +0800</pubDate>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2023 20:43:08 +0800</lastBuildDate>
        <category>coding</category>
        <category>algorithms</category>
        <category>Compilers</category>
        <category>computer science</category>
        <category>learning</category>
        <category>Django</category>
        <category>Python</category>
        <category>computer graphics</category>
        <category>Redis</category>
        <category>trash</category>
        <category>Java</category>
        <category>English</category>
        <category>test</category>
        <category>vim</category>
        <category>Spring</category>
        <category>Math</category>
        <category>Linear Algebra</category>
        <category>software engineering</category>
        <category>data structure</category>
        <category>Physics</category>
        <category>Discrete Mathematics</category>
        <category>coursera</category>
        <category>tree</category>
        <item>
            <guid isPermalink="true">https://blog.ivansnow02.xyz/TheFallingSoldier/</guid>
            <title>The Power of Robert Capa&#39;s The Falling Soldier</title>
            <link>https://blog.ivansnow02.xyz/TheFallingSoldier/</link>
            <category>English</category>
            <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2023 20:43:08 +0800</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[ &lt;p&gt;Today, I would like to talk about one of the most famous and controversial war photographs ever taken: &amp;quot;The Falling Soldier&amp;quot; by Robert Capa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-src=&#34;TheFallingSoldier/the_falling_soldier.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;The Falling Soldier - Robert Capa&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Robert Capa, born Endre Friedmann in 1913, was a Hungarian-born American photojournalist known for his courage and his motto: &amp;quot;If your pictures aren&#39;t good enough, you&#39;re not close enough.&amp;quot; He co-founded Magnum Photos, the first cooperative agency for freelance photographers. During his career, he covered several wars including the Spanish Civil War, World War II, and the First Indochina War. Tragically, he died in 1954 when he stepped on a landmine in Vietnam.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;The Falling Soldier&amp;quot; is a black and white photograph taken on 1936, during the Spanish Civil War. It captures the exact moment a Republican soldier is shot in the head and falls backward, seemingly lifeless. The photograph became a symbol of the Republican cause and the horrors of war.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;The Falling Soldier&amp;quot; is a powerful image that evokes various themes. The theme of death is prominent, as the photograph captures the instant of death, a rare and shocking occurrence in photography. It raises ethical questions about the role of photography in depicting death. The theme of war is also evident, as the image represents the brutality and violence of war and how it affects ordinary people caught in its crossfire. Finally, the theme of heroism is present, portraying the soldier as a hero who sacrificed his life for his cause.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I look at this photograph, I feel a mix of emotions. I feel sadness and anger, thinking about the unfairness of this soldier&#39;s death and the many others who perished in war. I also feel amazed and curious, appreciating Capa&#39;s incredible ability to capture such a momentous event with his camera.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, Robert Capa&#39;s &amp;quot;The Falling Soldier&amp;quot; is an iconic photograph that has left an indelible mark on the history of photojournalism. It is a powerful reminder of the horrors of war and the price paid by those who fight for their beliefs. The photograph&#39;s authenticity may remain a point of debate, but its impact on the world cannot be denied. Thank you for listening.&lt;/p&gt;
 ]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermalink="true">https://blog.ivansnow02.xyz/healthy-lifestyle/</guid>
            <title>Why Students Should Be Encouraged To Lead A Healthy Lifestyle</title>
            <link>https://blog.ivansnow02.xyz/healthy-lifestyle/</link>
            <category>English</category>
            <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2023 09:21:01 +0800</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[ &lt;p&gt;According to the World Health Organization, more than 80% of the world’s adolescents are insufficiently physically active. This alarming statistic shows that many students neglect their health in pursuit of academic excellence or other goals. However, health is not something that can be sacrificed or ignored. I believe that students should be encouraged to lead a healthy lifestyle by schools, families and society. While the physical benefits of doing so are widely recognized, I want to emphasize its positive effects on our mental health.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Health is the foundation of happiness. By engaging in regular exercise, eating a balanced diet, and getting sufficient sleep, one can not only prevent illnesses and boost the immune system, but also lower stress levels and anxiety. Moreover, a healthy lifestyle can enhance students’ academic performance, which is of utmost importance for us students. For instance, I used to sleep only 5 hours a day and rarely exercise when I was in high school.  Soon I suffered from a severe headache and lost concentration on my studies. As a result, my grades plummeted and this in turn made me more anxious and even harder to fall asleep. One day I decided to change the unhealthy lifestyle. I started to go to bed earlier and keep jogging. It really worked! I felt more energetic and confident than ever before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, leading a healthy lifestyle is not only beneficial for students’ physical health, but also for their mental well-being and academic performance. As far as I am concerned, at no time should we underestimate the benefits of leading a healthy lifestyle.&lt;/p&gt;
 ]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermalink="true">https://blog.ivansnow02.xyz/Sports-Life-Lesson/</guid>
            <title>Sports Life Lesson</title>
            <link>https://blog.ivansnow02.xyz/Sports-Life-Lesson/</link>
            <category>English</category>
            <pubDate>Sun, 14 May 2023 10:16:25 +0800</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[ &lt;p&gt;As Aristotle said, “Life needs sports.” Sport, in its various forms, is an integral part of human culture that transcends geographical, cultural, and linguistic boundaries. It is not only an avenue to maintain a better figure or a source of entertainment, but also a powerful means of character development and learning essential life lessons. Today, we will discuss some of the most important life lessons that sport can offer us beyond the playing field or court.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First and foremost, sport teaches us the value of hard work and perseverance. Higher, Faster, Stronger - the road to the top never comes to an end and being an athlete requires years of training, sweating and discipline. These qualities of dedication and hard work are essential for success in any endeavor, not just sport. When facing challenges, athletes learn to push themselves through adversity and focus on their goals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another lesson sport can teach us is how to work as a team. Most sports require cooperation as a team to achieve a common goal, such as scoring points or winning a match. Learning to work together, communicate effectively, and trust one another is crucial for success in any team-oriented environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, sport helps individuals develop a strong sense of self-confidence and self-awareness. As athletes improve their skills and achieve personal milestones, they gain confidence in their abilities, which can carry over to other areas of life. At the same time, sport requires individuals to recognize their strengths and weaknesses, promoting self-awareness and personal growth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sport has the power to change the world. The lessons learned on the field can have a lasting impact on an individual’s life and guide them to success.&lt;/p&gt;
 ]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermalink="true">https://blog.ivansnow02.xyz/making-friends/</guid>
            <title>The Best Way For A Student To Make Friends</title>
            <link>https://blog.ivansnow02.xyz/making-friends/</link>
            <category>English</category>
            <pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2023 11:31:21 +0800</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[ &lt;p&gt;Friendship is an essential aspect of a student’s life that fosters personal growth and emotional well-being by providing support, encouragement, and companionship. However, making friends can be daunting for some students, especially when seeking meaningful connections. Fortunately, there are some effective strategies that you can use to make friends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first step is &lt;strong&gt;to be open and approachable&lt;/strong&gt;. For example, a simple smile can break the ice between strangers. A friendly attitude creates a comfortable atmosphere and makes others feel welcomed. By being approachable, you signal to others that you are open to conversations and building connections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Participating actively in extracurricular activities and clubs&lt;/strong&gt; is another proven way of making friends that enriches your academic and social life. By engaging in shared interests, you will bond with like-minded people and nurture new friendships.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s important to remember that &lt;em&gt;a friend without faults will never be found&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;strong&gt;Try to be patient and tolerant of diversity among people&lt;/strong&gt;. Do not judge people based on appearance, background, or opinions. Try to learn from others and respect differences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Be slow in choosing a friend&lt;/em&gt;. Building meaningful connections requires &lt;strong&gt;patience and persistence&lt;/strong&gt;. Do not be discouraged if friendships do not form immediately. Continue putting yourself in social situations and engaging with others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The only way to have a friend is to be one&lt;/em&gt;. I believe the best way for students to make friends is to become their best selves. Therefore, by following these strategies, you will not only form lasting bonds and relationships, but also form a whole new self.&lt;/p&gt;
 ]]></description>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
